Total Experience: 14 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Electronics/Telecommunication]

Notice Period: Currently Serving Notice Period



Niraj 13.6 Years Experience in C# Using .Net Framework Azure Azure Devops Azure Service Bus Angular Can join immediately

Current Designation: Principal Software Engineer

Current Company: Dell International Services

Current Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Married

Key Skills: C# With .NET 2.0/3.5/4.0/4.5,ASP.NET2.0/3.5/4.0/4.5,SQL SERVER 2000/2005/2008/2012,Java Sript, Jquery, Jquery UI, AJAX, WPF, WCF, WCF REST, LINQ, Knockout Js, Require Js, XML, XSLT, ASP. NET

MVC3/MVC4/MVC5,ASP.NET Web API,CSS 3.0,Angular js,Azure,Powershell,Big

Verified: Email - id Phone Number |

Last Active: Jan-Mar 2021 Last Modified: Jan-Mar 2021

Summary

I Niraj Kumar have over 10 years of experience in Windows and Web application development using Microsoft .Net Platform. I have been involved in developing Windows and web based application, designing UI and writing business Logic. I was also involved in requirement collection and creating test description for the application. I have worked in database design. I have worked on different Windows and UNIX operating systems. I have done my Bachelor of Engineering in Electronics and Communication from V.N.E.C Bellary, Vishweshwaraiah Technological University. I am currently working for IGS for last 21 months. I have recently worked on Cloud based technology and also on new front end technologies like Angular and Knockout, Nodejs

Work Experience

Dell International Services as Principal Software Engineer

Jun 2017 to Till Date

Working as Architect for Data Science analytics an Chat Bot mostly using .NET frawework. Bots have become a revolution in creating personalized content and textual conversations that are relatively easy to deploy at scale. Bots are really good at catering to each client/customer on a real time basis.

All sorts of services are being "botmized" (See what I did there?). Using bots, we have the freedom to tackle interesting questions.

Synechron Technologies as Associate Specialist Technology Aug 2015 to Jun 2017

IGS as Technical Lead Jul 2013 to Aug 2015

Coding and Debugging, Unit test, Deploying

Neudesic Technology Private Limited as Senior Consultant Jul 2012 to Jul 2013

- Understanding Software Requirement Specification document
- Development business logic, presentation layer, database layer Support in Training, UAT and Production environments
- Code Review, Coding and debugging
- Deployment of the Web Services on Web Server(i.e. IIS)
- Unit and System Testing

HP GlobalSoft Limited as Technology Consultant

Jul 2011 to Jul 2012

- Understanding Software Requirement Specification document
- Development business logic, presentation layer, database layer Support in Training, UAT and Production environments
- Code Review, Coding and debugging
- Deployment of the Web Services on Web Server(i.e. IIS)
- Unit and System Testing

Tata Consultancy Services Limited (TCS) as Senior Programmer Jul 2010 to Jul 2012

3 YEARS EXPERIENCE C# Programming using .Net Framework 1.1, 2.0, 3.5, SQL SERVER 2000, 2005, 2008

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Electronics/Telecommunication) from Visveswaraiah Technological University (VTU) in 2006

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience	
C#		2017	4 Year(s) 3 Month(s)	
.NET		2017	4 Year(s) 6 Month(s)	
MERCURY		2017	1 Year(s)	
SQL Server		2017	3 Year(s) 0 Month(s)	
Angular js		2017	2 Year(s)	
Knockout JS		2015	2 Year(s)	
Node JS		2017	2 Year(s)	
SQL Azure		2017	2 Year(s)	
Windows Azure		2017	2 Year(s)	
ASP.NET SignalR		2017	2 Year(s)	
WCF		2017	3 Year(s)	
ASP.NET Web API		2017	2 Year(s)	
TFS	2012,2010	2017	5 Year(s)	
HTML5		2017	2 Year(s)	
JavaScript		2017	8 Year(s)	
BOOTSTRAP		2017	2 Year(s)	
ASP.Net MVC	3, 4, 5	2016	3 Year(s)	
LINQ		2015	4 Year(s)	
ASP.NET IDENTITY		2017	1 Year(s)	
WPF		2017	2 Year(s)	

Windows Form	2009	2 Year(s)
Windows Azure Storage	2015	1 Year(s)
XML	2017	5 Year(s)
JSON	2017	3 Year(s)
ASP.NET Web forms	2017	6 Year(s)
POWERSHELL	2017	1 Year(s)
Windows Azure Mobile Services	2015	1 Year(s)

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English	Proficient			
Hindi	Expert			

Projects

Project Title: Meridium V 4.0

Client: Meridium

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Jan 2015 - Till Date Onsite / Offsite: Offsite Project Location: Bangalore Role: Sr. Programmer Team Size: 14

Skill Used: HTML5, Javascript, JQuery, CSS, Angularis, Windows Azure appfabric, Web api 2.0, ASP.NET Signal R2, ASP.NET MVC, C#, SQL SERVER 2008 R2, SQL Azure, Powershell, Bootstrap, Windows azure ACS, Selenium using C#

Role Description: I work as Senior software engineer.

Project Details: Meridium V 4.0 is asset performance application used by oil, gas, and coal caompanies

Project Title: Gabriel

Client: MSA

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Jul 2013 - Dec 2014 Project Location: Bangalore Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Role: Module Leader Team Size: 6

Skill Used: ASP.NET MVC5, Web API 2.0, Windows Azure, Angular js, jquery, Entity framework 6.0, SQL SE, Selenium using

C#

Role Description: Designing, coding, debugging, unit testing

Project Details: Gabriel Dashboard web application built using ASP.NET MVC5, Web API 2.0, Windows Azure Appfabric, Angular js, Node js, jquery, Entity framework 6.0. Application is used to for creating reports and it is in media doamin,

Project Title: PTI

Client: American Express

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Jul 2010 - Apr 2011 Project Location: Bangalore Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Team Size: 4 Role: Programmer

Skill Used: C# .NET for creating Web Services using WCF.

Role Description: .Net Developer. Project Details: C#, XSSLT, XML, XSD

PTI stands for Product Transfer Infrastructure involves three Composite Web Services GTO, VTO and ITP, ITPV2, ITPV3, Batch Utility which basically responsible for performing product transfer. These three Web services are SOAP based Web services. Various front end SSP, MYCA uses these Web Services to perform product transfer. These web services interact with different backend like Triumph (fixed length format), PMC(DB2 backend), CAS, BPM

Project Title: HEO & ORDERS TOOLKIT

Client: McKesson

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Jan 2007 - Jan 2008 Project Location: Bangalore Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Team Size: 11 Role: Test Engineer

Skill Used: Mercury Quality Center, StarTeam, Knowledge Base, QTP

Role Description: Software Tester

Project Details: HEO & ORDERS TOOLKIT is once again a product from Mckesson .lts Order Entry Application which is used in Hospitals in USA .This application is developed by Mckesson using .NET and Java Technology on Windows Form based

1/22/2021 https://freesearch.naukri.com/preview/printResume?uname=3c06b357115bb36b7088730d9f59a97b0c5f5b594e115b16054312595b...application.

Affirmative Action

Category: General

Physically Challenged: No

Work Authorization

Job Type: Permanent

Employment Status: Full time